[
  {
    "type": "text",
    "question": "Shaffer Company presents the following data for 2012. Net Sales, 2012 = $3,007,124; Net Sales, 2011 = $93,247; Cost of Goods Sold, 2012 = $2,000,326; Cost of Goods Sold, 2011 = $1,000,120; Inventory, beginning of 2012 = $341,169; Inventory, end of 2012 = $376,526. The merchandise inventory turnover for 2012 is:",
    "options": [
      "5.6.",
      "15.6.",
      "7.5.",
      "7.7.",
      "5.2."
    ],
    "correct": 0
  },
  {
    "type": "text",
    "question": "Liquidity ratios can be used:",
    "options": [
      "to measure the degree of protection of long-term suppliers of funds.",
      "to measure borrowing capacity.",
      "to measure the earning ability of a firm.",
      "to measure the firm's ability to meet its current obligations.",
      "to measure the worth of the firm."
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "type": "text",
    "question": "Which of the following types of businesses would normally have the shortest operating cycle?",
    "options": [
      "A retail clothing store",
      "A grocery store",
      "A wholesale furniture store",
      "A car manufacturer",
      "A car dealer"
    ],
    "correct": 1
  },
  {
    "type": "text",
    "question": "Jones Company presents the following data for 2012. Receivables, less allowance for losses and discounts of $12,196 = $266,700; Net Sales = $2,360,108; Cost of Goods Sold = $1,580,360. The days' sales in receivables are:",
    "options": [
      "53.1.",
      "48.2.",
      "43.1.",
      "38.1.",
      "40.0."
    ],
    "correct": 2
  },
  {
    "type": "text",
    "question": "Abbott Company presents the following data for 2012. Receivables, end of year, less allowances for losses and discounts of $115,960 = $2,370,100; Receivables, beginning of year, less allowance for losses and discounts of $102,330 = $2,443,140; Net Sales = $24,417,090. The accounts receivable turnover in times per year is:",
    "options": [
      "6.9.",
      "7.9.",
      "10.7.",
      "9.7.",
      "11.0."
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "type": "text",
    "question": "Gross profit is the difference between:",
    "options": [
      "net income and operating income.",
      "revenues and expenses.",
      "sales and cost of goods sold.",
      "income from continuing operations and discontinued operations.",
      "gross sales and sales discounts."
    ],
    "correct": 2
  },
  {
    "type": "text",
    "question": "Which of the following would be included in operating income?",
    "options": [
      "Interest income for a manufacturing firm",
      "Rent income for a leasing subsidiary",
      "Gain from sale of marketable securities for a retailer",
      "Dividend income for a service firm",
      "None of the answers are correct."
    ],
    "correct": 1
  },
  {
    "type": "text",
    "question": "The following relate to Data Original in 2012. Purchases = $540,000; Beginning Inventory = $80,000; Purchase Returns = $10,000; Sales = $800,000; Cost of Goods Sold = $490,000. What is the ending inventory?",
    "options": [
      "$120,000",
      "$140,000",
      "$210,000",
      "$260,000",
      "none of the answers are correct"
    ],
    "correct": 0
  },
  {
    "type": "text",
    "question": "Changes in account balances of Multi-Plus Inc. during 2012 were: Assets = $420,000; Liabilities = $125,000; Capital Stock = $100,000; Additional Paid-In Capital = $140,000; Retained Earnings = ?. Assuming that there were no charges to retained earnings other than dividends of $62,000, the net income for 2010 was:",
    "options": [
      "($7,000)",
      "$55,000",
      "$117,000",
      "$257,000",
      "none of the answers are correct"
    ],
    "correct": 2
  },
  {
    "type": "text",
    "question": "Gross profit is the difference between:",
    "options": [
      "net income and operating income.",
      "revenues and expenses.",
      "sales and cost of goods sold.",
      "income from continuing operations and discontinued operations.",
      "gross sales and sales discounts."
    ],
    "correct": 2
  },
  {
    "type": "text",
    "question": "Which of the following would be included in operating income?",
    "options": [
      "Interest income for a manufacturing firm",
      "Rent income for a leasing subsidiary",
      "Gain from sale of marketable securities for a retailer",
      "Dividend income for a service firm",
      "None of the answers are correct."
    ],
    "correct": 1
  },
  {
    "type": "text",
    "question": "Which of the following would be classified as an extraordinary item on the income statement?",
    "options": [
      "Loss from a strike",
      "Correction of an error related to a prior period",
      "Write-off of obsolete inventory",
      "Loss on disposal of a segment of business",
      "Loss from prohibition of a product"
    ],
    "correct": 4
  },
  {
    "type": "text",
    "question": "Which of the following will not affect retained earnings?",
    "options": [
      "Declaration of a stock dividend",
      "Payment of a cash dividend previously disclosed",
      "Adjustment for an error of a prior period",
      "Net income",
      "Net loss"
    ],
    "correct": 1
  },
  {
    "type": "text",
    "question": "Statements in which all items are expressed only in relative terms (percentages of a base) are termed:",
    "options": [
      "vertical Statements.",
      "horizontal Statements.",
      "funds Statements.",
      "common-Size Statements.",
      "None of the answers are correct."
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "type": "text",
    "question": "Which of the following would not be a user of financial statements?",
    "options": [
      "Management",
      "Bankers",
      "Employee unions",
      "Investment analysts",
      "All of the answers are users."
    ],
    "correct": 4
  },
  {
    "type": "text",
    "question": "Which of the following current assets will not generate cash in the future?",
    "options": [
      "Prepayments",
      "Accounts receivable",
      "Inventory",
      " Marketable securities",
      "Notes receivable"
    ],
    "correct": 0
  },
  {
    "type": "text",
    "question": "Which of the following ratios would generally be used to evaluate a firm's overall liquidity position?",
    "options": [
      "Working capital",
      "Current ratio",
      "Acid-test ratio",
      "Cash ratio",
      "Inventory turnover in days"
    ],
    "correct": 1
  },
  {
    "type": "text",
    "question": "Liquidity ratios can be used:",
    "options": [
      "to measure the degree of protection of long-term suppliers of funds.",
      "to measure borrowing capacity.",
      "to measure the earning ability of a firm.",
      "to measure the firm's ability to meet its current obligations.",
      "to measure the worth of the firm."
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "type": "text",
    "question": "Which of the following types of businesses would normally have the shortest operating cycle?",
    "options": [
      "A retail clothing store",
      "A grocery store",
      "A wholesale furniture store",
      "A car manufacturer",
      "A car dealer"
    ],
    "correct": 1
  },
  {
    "type": "text",
    "question": "Which of the following would not be a user of financial statements?",
    "options": [
      "Management",
      "Bankers",
      "Employee unions",
      "Investment analysts",
      "All of the answers are users."
    ],
    "correct": 4
  }
]